Robert Houghwout Jackson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Correspondence, 1912-1954 (Box 9-22)
  - Douglas, William O.
  - Durkin, John E.
  - "E" miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Edgerton, Henry W.
  - Edson, Walter H.
  - Emmons, Ralph L.
  - Ernst, Morris L.
  - Everett, Willis M.
  - "F" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - Fahy, Charles
  - Fairman, Charles
  - Farley, James A.
  - Fisher, Marion H.
  - Fletcher, Milton J.
  - Frank, Jerome N. (Box 13)
  - Frankfurter, Felix
  - Freund, Paul
  - Fyfe, Sir David Maxwell
  - "G" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Gardner, Warner W.
  - Garfield, Frederick M.
  - Goodrich, Herbert F.
  - Gregory, Tappan
  - Griswold, Erwin N.
  - "H" miscellaneous
    - Ha-Hi, (2 folders)
    - Ho-Hu (Box 14)
  - Halpern, Philip
  - Hand, Learned
  - Harris, Whitney R.
  - Herrick, Gerald
  - Hoover, J. Edgar
  - "I" miscellaneous
  - Ickes, Harold L.
  - "J" miscellaneous
  - Johansen, John C.
  - "K" miscellaneous
  - Kent, Arthur H.
  - Knopf, Alfred A. and Blanche, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Krieger, John G.
  - "L" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Lauterpacht, Hirsch
  - Legal Aid Society
  - Lerner, Max
  - "M" miscellaneous
    - Ma
    - Mc-Mu, (3 folders) (Box 16)
  - Magill, Roswell
  - Malcolmson, Charles
  - Manley, Henry S.
  - Marsh, James
  - Marston, Otis
  - McAllister, Thomas F.
  - McLaurin, Campbell
  - McRuer, James C.
  - Minton, Sherman
  - Morrison, Earle R. (Box 17)
  - Murphy, Frank
  - "N" miscellaneous
  - National Legal Aid Association
  - Neal, Phil C.
  - Niebank, C. George
  - "O" miscellaneous
  - O'Brian, John Lord
  - Odlum, Floyd
  - "P" miscellaneous
    - Pa-Pe, (2 folders)
    - Pf-Pu, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Parker, John J.
  - Patterson, Richard C.
  - Patterson, Robert P.
  - Perlman, Philip B.
  - Pike, Melicent
  - Poletti, Charles
  - Powell, Thomas Reed
  - Prettyman, E. Barrett
  - "Q" miscellaneous
  - "R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - Ramaswamy, M.
  - Ransom, William L. (Box 19)
  - Reed, Stanley Forman
  - Rehnquist, William H.
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. and Eleanor
  - Rutledge, Wiley
  - "S" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
  - Schjelderup, Ferdinand
  - Schuyler, Clyde H.
  - Sears, Charles B. (Box 20)
  - Shawcross, Hartley Shawcross, Baron
  - Shea, Francis
  - Smith, Willis
  - Society for the Prevention of World War III
  - Spencer, Lavern
  - Steinbrink, Meier
  - Sternberg, Ruth
  - Stettinius, Edward R.
  - Stoessel, Oskar
  - Stone, Harlan F.
  - Storey, Robert G.
  - Stryker, Lloyd Paul
  - Svanstrom, Ragnar and Greta
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard
  - "T" miscellaneous
  - Taylor, Telford
  - Tobin, Frederick M.
  - Tubbs, Warren
  - Tweed, Harrison
  - "U" miscellaneous
  - Unidentified
  - United States Flag Association
  - Upton, J. Duane
  - "V" miscellaneous (Box 21)
  - Vinson, Fred M.
  - "W" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Walsh, Edmund A.
  - Warren, Earl
  - Warren, Lucian C.
  - Wehle, Louis A.
  - Wickser, Philip J.
  - Willard, Mary and Vesta
  - Wright, John H.
  - Wyzanski, Charles E.
  - "Y"-"Z" miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 22)
    - Crank letters
    - Invitations, 1942-1954
    - Misdirected letters of Robert Jackson, attorney, Shoreham Building
    - Publications received, 1947-1954
    - Recommendations, (2 folders)
    - Requests for assistance
    - Requests for photographs
- Subject File, 1931-1954 (Box 23-31)
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person or organization and topic.
  - American Bar Association (Box 23)
    - General, (2 folders)
    - Luncheon given by Jackson, 19 Sept. 1950
    - Special Committee on the Administration of Criminal Justice
      - Committee meetings, 1953-1954, (2 folders)
      - Director of research
      - Expenses (Box 24)
      - Ford Foundation grant
      - General, 1953-1954, (3 folders)
      - Press coverage (Box 25)
      - Response from the public
      - Survey of the administration of justice, (2 folders)
  - American Bar Research Center, 1952-1954, (3 folders)
  - American Society of International Law
  - Black, Hugo LaFayette
  - Black, Hugo LaFayette, controversy with Jackson (Box 26)
    - Clippings
    - Jackson's account of the controversy
    - Jackson's cables from Nuremberg, Germany
    - Reaction to Jackson's cable from Nuremberg, Germany, to the House and Senate Judiciary committees
  - Bohemian Club
    - 1948-1952, (4 folders)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 27)
  - Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of Government
  - Commission on the Administration of Justice in New York, 1931-1936 See also Oversize, (2 folders)
  - Czechoslovakians
  - Federal Bar Association
  - Friends of the Library of Congress (Box 28)
  - Fund for the Republic
  - Fyfe, Sir David Maxwell, luncheon, 8 Sept. 1954
  - George Washington University, Washington, D.C.
    - Board of Trustees, 1951-1954, (3 folders)
    - Foreign Law Society
  - Germans, visitors and requests for aid from Nuremberg, Germany, citizens, 1948-1954
  - Inns of Court restoration
  - Inter-American Bar Association, meeting, Havana, Cuba, 1941 (Box 29)
  - International criminal court
  - Jamestown Bar Association Library, Jamestown, N.Y.
  - Judiciary Act of 1937
  - Kiantone movement
  - Lauterpacht, H., memorandum on principles of international law involved in United States measures taken against Germany between Sept. 1940 and Dec. 1941
  - Moot court competitions
  - National Institute of Public Affairs
  - National Lawyers Guild, 1936-1940, (2 folders)
  - Presidential campaigns (Box 30)
    - 1936 platform
    - 1940 campaign
    - 1940 platform, (2 folders)
  - Preston, Homer, estate of
  - Retirement of judges
  - Riccobono Seminar of Roman Law in America, Catholic University, Washington, D.C.
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
  - Smithsonian Institution, International Exchange Service
  - Stockholm, Sweden, petition to ban atom bomb
  - "Strike of Capital," use of phrase by Jackson in speech before the American Political Science Association, 1937
  - Trail Riders of the Wilderness, Sawtooth, Idaho, expedition (Box 31)
  - Warren, Earl, appointment as chief justice
  - Zivkovic, R.
- Speeches and Writings File, 1911-1955 (Box 31-58)
  Speeches, articles, drafts, speech notes and outlines, book reviews, poems, related correspondence, and printed matter.
  Separated by speeches and writings and arranged chronologically therein.
  - Indexes (Box 31)
    - Card file See Container 250
    - Lists
  - Speeches
    - Oct. 1912-Dec. 1930, (43 folders)
    - June 193l-Dec. 1935, (38 folders) (Box 32)
    - Jan. 1936-Aug. 1937, (29 folders) (Box 33)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1937, (13 folders) (Box 34)
    - Jan.-Feb. 1938, (8 folders) (Box 35)
    - Mar.-Nov. 1938, (14 folders) (Box 36)
    - Nov. 1938-Apr. 1939, (13 folders) (Box 37)
    - May-July 1939, (14 folders) (Box 38)
    - Aug. 1939-June 1940, (25 folders) (Box 39)
    - Aug.-Dec. 1940, (21 folders) (Box 40)
    - Jan.-Nov. 1941, (17 folders) (Box 41)
    - Jan.-May 1942, (17 folders) (Box 42)
    - Dec. 1944-May 1946, (15 folders) (Box 43)
    - Oct. 1946-June 1947, (16 folders) (Box 44)
    - July 1947-Aug. 1948, (19 folders) (Box 45)
    - Sept. 1948-June 1949, (11 folders) (Box 46)
    - Sept. 1949-Dec. 1950, (12 folders) (Box 47)
    - Jan.-Dec. 1951, (10 folders) (Box 48)
    - Feb.-Dec. 1952, (10 folders) (Box 49)
    - Jan.-Oct. 1953, (12 folders) (Box 50)
    - Nov. 1953-Dec. 1954, (8 folders) (Box 51)
    - 1954, (5 folders) (Box 52)
    - 1954-1955, (6 folders) (Box 53)
    - Undated
  - Speech notes and outlines, circa 1928, 1946-1948, undated, (2 folders)
  - Writings (Box 54)
    - 1911, Jan., letter to the editor of Atlantic Monthly
    - 1927, Dec., "What Price 'Due Process'?" New York Law Review
    - 1929, June, "Functions of the Trust Company in the Field of Law"
    - 1930
      - Feb., "Trial Practice in Negligence Litigation," published, Cornell Law Review, with title "Trial Practice in Accident Litigation"
      - Dec., report of Committee on Litigation Affecting Personal Injuries
      - "The Future of the Bar"
    - 1931, Feb.," Bar Associations Viewed by New Vice President," New York State Bar Association Bulletin
    - 1932
      - June, "A Lawyer Looks at Politics," Jeffersonian
      - Review of the report of the Commission on Administrative Justice
    - 1933, Jan., "The Judicial Council, Its Function and Need," New York State Bar Association Bulletin
    - 1935
      - 28 Aug., "The Rich Get Richer," New Republic
      - 30 Aug., "Memorandum on National Wealth and Its Distribution," Annalist
      - 4 Sept., "The Big Corporations Rule," New Republic
      - "Memorandum as to Graduated Corporation Income Tax and Intercorporate Dividend Tax," Bureau of Internal Revenue
    - 1936
      - Jan., "The People's Business: The Truth about Taxes," Forum
      - Sept., "America Has Only Scratched Her Resources," in "Are We Going Broke? A Debate on National Finances," Forum
      - 24 Oct., "Is Landon Constitutional?" Nation
    - 1937, Dec., "It's Up to Us," Commentator
    - 1938
      - Jan., "Monopolies and the Courts," University of Pennsylvania Law Review
      - Dec., "Financial Monopoly: The Road to Socialism," Forum
    - 1939
      - May, "Anti-Semitism," We Hold These Truths, League of American Writers
      - Dec., review of The Administrative Process, by James M. Landis, for Journal of Social Philosophy
      - "Bank Competition with the Legal Profession"
    - 1940
      - Jan., "The Supreme Court and Interstate Barriers," Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science
      - Summer, message on launching of Bill of Rights Review, Bill of Rights Review
      - Aug., introduction to Our Constitution: Tool Or Testament, by Beryl Harold Levy
      - Sept., foreword to The Law of National Banking, by William V. O'Connor
      - 22 Oct., "Why Roosevelt Will Win," Look (Box 55)
      - Nov.
        - "Message to Committee of Catholics for Human Rights," Voice for Human Rights
        - "Our Government Is Prepared against the Fifth Column," in "American vs. Fifth Columnists: A Symposium," Survey Graphic
    - 1941
      - July
        - Editorial, National Magazine
        - "The Judicial Career of Chief Justice Hughes," American Bar Association Journal
      - The Struggle for Judicial Supremacy, (3 folders)
    - 1942, "Statecraft under a Written Constitution," in Men of Tomorrow; Nine Leaders Discuss the Problems of American Youth, edited by Thomas H. Johnson
    - 1944, Mar., review of I Can Go Home Again, by Arthur G. Powell, in American Bar Association Journal
    - 1945
      - 7 June, report to the President of the United States on progress of plans for the prosecution of Axis war criminals
      - 9 Sept., "Worst Crime of All," New York Times Magazine
      - Full Faith and Credit: The Lawyer's Clause of the Constitution For additional material see Container 43, Speeches, 7 Dec. 1944
    - 1946
      - 6 Apr., "The Law under Which Nazi Organizations Are Accused of Being Criminal," Temple Law Quarterly
      - 29 May, "Some Lessons of the Nurnberg Trial," New York Times
    - 1947, Feb., "Closing Arguments for Conviction of Nazi War Criminals," Case and Comment (Box 56)
    - 1948
      - Nov., introduction to "Freemasonry a Prisoner of War," by Charles G. Hamilton, The New Age
      - Review of A Modern Law of Nations, by Philip C. Jessup, for New York Times Book Review
    - 1949
      - 15 June, introduction for Dictionary of Legal Terms and Phrases in English, Spanish, French and German, by Lawrence Egbert
      - Aug.-Sept., "Nurnberg in Retrospect," Canadian Bar Review
      - Dec., "Lawyer Reference Plans: A Manual for Bar Associations," American Bar Association Journal
    - 1950, 21 May, "Justice Jackson on Communism in America," New York Times Magazine, also published as "The Communists in America," Harper's, Sept. 1950 and as "Taft-Hartley and the Reds," Catholic Digest, July 1958
    - 1951, review of Charles Evans Hughes, by Merlo J. Pusey, in the Washington Post
    - 1951-1961, endorsement for Legal Aid in the United States, by Emery A. Brownell, published, Westport, Conn., Greenwood Press, 1971
    - 1952, "Falstaff's Descendants in Pennsylvania Courts," University of Pennsylvania Law Review, (3 folders)
    - 1953 (Box 57)
      - June, "A Presidential Legal Opinion," Harvard Law Review
      - Aug., "Criminal Justice: The Vital Problem of the Future," report of the American Bar Association's Special Committee on the Administration of Criminal Justice
      - Introduction for Jurisprudence in Action, the Association of the Bar of the City of New York; introduction written in 1951
    - 1954
      - Introduction for Tyranny on Trial, by Whitney R. Harris
      - Foreword for Law in the Middle East, by Majid Khadduri
      - "The Exchange of Destroyers for Atlantic Bases," unpublished, (2 folders)
    - Undated
      - Article on the impact of the Social Security tax on the campaign and election of 1936
      - Letters to editors of the Washington Post and the Jamestown Journal, Jamestown, N.Y.
      - "Just Vagrant Thoughts," notebook of poems
      - Miscellany
      - Poems
  - Invitations to speak or to contribute manuscripts for publication, 1937-1954, (5 folders) (Box 58)
- Legal File, 1919-1962 (Box 59-188)
  Affidavits, briefs, collected data, correspondence, general office files, memoranda, petitions, opinions, and printed matter.
  Arranged by major career divisions. Arrangement within career divisions is either alphabetical or chronological based on the files involved.
  The Nuremberg War Crimes Trial files, containers 95-106 [microfilm shelf no. 22,796] and containers 107-118, [microfilm shelf no. 22,872] are available on microfilm.
  - Jamestown, N.Y., law practice (Box 59)
    - Chautauqua County Bankers' Association & Jamestown Clearing House, brief opposing recommendations of Robert Moses
    - Chautauqua Traction Co.
    - City of Jamestown v. Jamestown St. Ry.
    - City of Jamestown v. Pennsylvania Gas Co.
      - Vols. 2-3
      - Vols. 4-5 (Box 60)
    - Gates v. Prudential Ins. Co. (Typhoid carrier case)
    - Hall, Carroll M.
    - Hydraulic Race Co. v. Niagara Falls Milling Co. (Box 61)
    - Jamestown, Westfield & Northwestern R.R.
      - Administration of Brodhead estates, (3 folders)
      - Clippings
      - Correspondence, 1928-1941
      - Jamestown, N.Y., Chamber of Commerce v. Jamestown Westfield & Northwestern R.R., (3 folders) (Box 62)
    - Jamestown Worsted Mills
      - Central Union Trust Co. v. Jamestown Worsted Mills
        - Transcript of trial, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 63)
        - Other papers
      - Correspondence, 1927-1934
    - Miscellany, 1929-1936
    - New York Tel. Co. v. Jamestown Tel. Corp. (Box 64)
      - Briefs, (3 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1935-1943
      - Record on appeal, (1 folder) (Box 65)
      - Related papers
    - Niagara, Lockport, and Ontario Power Co. case, (4 folders)
    - Ohlquist v. Norstrom
    - Pike, Melicent
  - Assistant general counsel, Bureau of Internal Revenue (Box 66)
    - Appointment and resignation See also Oversize
    - Associated Gas and Electric Co.
    - Bull, Henry Adsit
    - Commission to Investigate the Administration of Justice in the State of New York
    - Detail to Securities and Exchange Commission
    - Interdepartmental requests for advice or assistance
    - International Match Co. case, (2 folders)
    - Kennedy, C. W.
    - Mellon, Andrew W., tax case
      - Brief on fraud issues, tentative outline, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence (Box 67)
      - Notes and evidence, (19 folders); (3 folders) (Box 68)
      - Opening statement, 18 Feb. 1935
      - Petitioners exhibits, (2 folders); (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 69, Box 70, Box 71, Box 72, Box 73, Box 74)
      - Procedures for dealing with fraudulent violations of Internal Revenue laws
      - Proposed article in the Saturday Evening Post
      - Stipulations of fact
    - Miscellany (Box 75)
    - New York Public Service Commission offer
    - Personnel problems and irregularities
    - Procedures and policy
    - Recommendations for political appointments to federal positions
    - Revenue Act of 1935, (5 folders)
    - Tax case congestion (Box 76)
    - Tax cases, miscellaneous
    - Tax studies
      - Ford Motor Co.
      - Income and income taxes, (2 folders)
      - Internal Revenue Service collections
      - Personal notebook (index tabbed)
    - Taxability of contributions to teachers' retirement plans (Box 77)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission, Electric Bond and Share Co. case
  - Justice Department
    - Assistant attorney general, Tax Division
      - Appointment
      - Miscellany
      - Social Security cases
        - Other cases
        - Pulaski Trucking Co. v. Newark Milk Co.
    - Assistant attorney general, Antitrust Division
      - Aluminum Co. of America
      - Antitrust Division matters
      - Appointment
      - Arnold, Thurman Wesley
      - Associated Gas and Electric Co. (Box 78)
      - Attorney general
      - Automobile financing
      - B & G Garment Co. case
      - Fishing trip with Franklin D. Roosevelt, 27 Nov.-6 Dec. 1937
      - Geiger, Ferdinant A., hearing before the Judiciary Committee of the House of Representatives regarding conduct of
      - Identical bids
      - Labor unions
      - Louisiana cases
      - MacFarlan, Malcolm, estate of
      - Milk investigations
      - Motion picture industry
      - Oil cases (Box 79)
      - Panhandle E. Pipe Line Co. v. Columbia Gas & Elec. Co.
      - Podell, David L.
      - Proposed tax investigation, 1937
      - Reorganization and operation of the division
      - Reorganization of federal judiciary
      - Resignation
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D., monopoly message
      - Tax status of Eleanor Roosevelt's income from broadcasts, Jackson's statement, 28 July 1937
      - Tydings-Miller Bill
      - United States v. American Soc'y of Composers, Authors & Publishers
      - United States v. Appalachian Elec. Power Co. (water power case)
      - Wages and Hours Act (Box 80)
      - Western Union
    - Solicitor general
      - Aircraft production legislation, (2 folders)
      - Alien property legislation
      - American Law Institute, messages from the president
      - American League for Peace and Democracy
      - American Line S.S. Corp. v. United States
      - Anti-Semitic propaganda
      - Antitrust laws and labor organizations
      - Appointment and confirmation
        - Briefing material for hearings
        - Hearings (Box 81)
        - Letters of congratulations
      - Appointment of Frank Murphy as attorney general
      - Attorney general, miscellaneous memoranda to and from
      - Bankruptcy legislation
      - Cardozo, Benjamin, memorial at Supreme Court, 26 Nov. 1938
      - Case v. Los Angeles Lumber Co.
      - Chaco arms embargo
      - Child labor amendment cases
      - City of Atlanta v. National Bituminous Coal Comm'n
      - Curran v. Wallace
      - Federal Communications Comm'n v. Pottsville Broadcasting Co.
      - Franklin D. Roosevelt Library, Hyde Park, N.Y.
      - Gerhardt decision, prospective application of (Box 82)
      - Germany, sale of helium to
      - Hale v. Bimco Trading
      - Hot oil case
      - Interstate Circuit v. United States
      - Jackson's service as acting attorney general
      - Jameson & Co. v. Morgenthau
      - Kessler v. Strecker
      - Lamb, Edward, contempt of court and disbarment proceedings
      - Meeting re extension of Civil Service System to legal departments and agencies, 23 Aug. 1938
      - Milk control cases
      - Miscellany
      - Mulford v. Smith
      - Neutrality Proclamation, 5 Sept. 1939 (Box 83)
      - Office matters, miscellaneous
      - O'Malley v. Woodrough
      - Paramount Pictures v. United States See Container 82, Interstate Circuit v. United States
      - Parker v. Elg
      - Pittman v. Home Owners' Loan Corp.
      - Poll tax as a prerequisite to voting
      - Price control legislation
      - Procedure for handling matters in lower courts
      - Proclamation of national emergency, 7 Sept. 1939
      - Proposed articles re third term for Franklin D. Roosevelt
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D., "State of the Union" message, 3 Jan. 1940, second draft
      - Rumely, Edward A., punishment for contempt charges of Special Committee to Investigate Lobbying Activities
      - Safeguarding defense secrets
      - Shields v. Utah-Idaho Cent. R.R.
      - State Tax Comm'rs of Utah v. Van Coit
      - Tax immunity data (Box 84)
      - Tax message by Franklin D. Roosevelt.
      - Tennessee Elec. Power Co. v. Tennessee Valley Auth.
      - Tennessee Valley Authority, removal of Arthur E. Morgan
      - United States v. Bekins
      - United States v. Manton
      - United States v. Morgan
      - Utah Fuel Co. v. National Bituminous Coal Comm'n
      - War profits tax, (1 folder) (Box 85)
      - White House, matters referred to Jackson
    - Attorney general
      - Advisory Commission to the Council of National Defense
      - Antitrust activities
        - Oil companies
        - Teamsters Union
        - War materials industries
      - Antitrust Division matters
      - Appointment and confirmation, (2 folders) (Box 86)
      - Associated Gas and Electric Co. cases
      - Bethlehem Steel Corp. case
      - Bridges, Harry, deportation of, (2 folders)
      - Budget matters
      - Butler, Pierce, memorial for
      - Cabinet meetings, Apr.-May 1941, Jackson's notes
      - Clark, Granville, requests for information on organizations opposing Burke-Wadsworth Bill
      - Coal strike opinion (Box 87)
      - Columbia Gas & Electric Corp.
      - Commissions signed by Jackson, 1940-1941
      - Committee on Administrative Procedure
      - Committee on Civil Rights
      - Correspondence with cabinet members
        - Interior Department
        - Labor Department
        - Navy Department
        - State Department
        - Treasury Department
        - War Department
      - Correspondence with Justice Dept. officials
        - Bennett, James V.
        - Biddle, Francis
        - Clark, Samuel
        - Holtzoff, Alexander (Box 88)
        - Lyons, David
        - Shea, Francis
      - Criminal Division
      - Daily memoranda by Jackson and secretarial staff, 1940-1941, (2 folders)
      - Deportation of convicts escaped from "Devil's Island"
      - Destroyer, naval bases exchange
      - Dismissal of indictments against recruiters for Spanish Loyalists (Box 89)
      - District of Columbia Bar Association, black lawyers
      - Domestic foreign language press
      - Economic controls, establishment of
      - Federal Bureau of Investigation, reports on maritime matters, 1940-194l
      - Federal judges
        - Appointment
        - Trials and behavior
      - Hatch Act
      - Hopkins, Harry
      - House Committee on Un-American Activities (Dies Committee), (2 folders)
      - Immigration and naturalization (Box 90)
        - Alien registration
        - Canada-United States border crossing procedures
        - Custody of German and Italian seamen
        - Deportation of aliens
        - Miscellany
        - Transfer of Immigration and Naturalization Service to Justice Dept.
      - Immobilized foreign ships
      - Inter-American Bar Association Conference, Havana, Cuba, 24 Mar. 1941
      - Internment of alien enemies
      - Jamestown, N.Y., post office site
      - Lands Division matters (Box 91)
      - Lend-Lease Act
      - Logan-Walter Bill, veto message, (2 folders)
      - McGuire, Matthew, re judicial appointments, (2 folders)
      - Memoranda re appointments to judicial vacancies, mainly from Franklin D. Roosevelt
      - Miscellany
      - Murals for Justice Dept. library
      - National defense (Box 92)
      - National Guard armories